When honor was everything.
The Green Knight is a adventure, drama, fantasy film directed by David Lowery.
An epic fantasy adventure based on the timeless Arthurian legend, The Green Knight tells the story of Sir Gawain, King Arthur's reckless and headstrong
nephew, who embarks on a daring quest to confront the eponymous Green Knight, a gigantic emerald-skinned stranger and tester of men.
Gawain, played by Dev Patel.
Lady / Essel, played by Alicia Vikander.
Lord, played by Joel Edgerton.
Mother, played by Sarita Choudhury.
King, played by Sean Harris.
Queen, played by Kate Dickie.
The Green Knight is a 2021 dark fantasy adventure film directed,
written, produced, and edited by David Lowery.
It is an adaptation from the anonymously written 14th-century poem Sir Gawain and the Green Knight and stars
Dev Patel as Gawain, who sets out on a journey to test his courage and face the Green Knight.
It also stars Alicia Vikander, Joel Edgerton, Sarita Choudhury, Sean
Harris, and Ralph Ineson as the titular character.
The Green Knight was theatrically released in the
United States on July 30, 2021, by A24.
The film received acclaim from critics for its cinematography, music, acting (particularly
Patel's), production values, and Lowery's originality, direction, and writing.
It grossed over $20 million against a budget of $15 million.
The film explores themes of winter, fox, camelot,
king arthur, middle ages (476-1453).
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.